25 years. Hundreds of victims. Justice for none.
Tales of the Grim Sleeper is a crime, documentary
film directed by Nick Broomfield.
When Lonnie Franklin Jr.
was arrested in South Central Los Angeles in 2010 as the suspected murderer of a string of young
black women, police hailed it as the culmination of 20 years of investigations.
Four years later documentary filmmaker Nick Broomfield took his camera
to the alleged killer’s neighborhood for another view.
Self, played by Lonnie Franklin Jr..
Lonnie David Franklin Jr.
(August 30, 1952 – March 28, 2020), better known by the nickname Grim Sleeper, was an American serial killer who was
responsible for at least ten murders and one attempted murder in Los Angeles, California from 1984 to 2007.
He was also convicted for rape and sexual violence.
Franklin earned his nickname when he appeared to have taken a
14-year break from his crimes, from 1988 to 2002.
In July 2010, Franklin was arrested as a suspect, and, after
many delays, his trial began in February 2016.
On May 5, 2016, the jury convicted him of killing
nine women and one teenage girl.
On June 6, 2016, the jury returned a verdict of guilty, and on August 10, 2016, the Los Angeles
Superior Court sentenced him to death for each of the ten victims named in the verdict.
On March 28, 2020, Franklin was found dead in his cell at San Quentin State
Prison though no cause of death was ever publicly revealed.